雅克，快来！
Jacques, come quick!
-它闪闪发光
快点，雅克！在港湾里闪闪发光！
- lt's shining!
- Quick, Jacques! lt's shining in the harbour!
快点！
Quick!
那里你看到了吗，雅克？
There! You see it, Jacques?
这是一枚硬币。
lt's a coin.
-是我的！我先看到的
不，你这个骗子！
- lt's mine! l saw it first!
- No, you liar!
-骗子！骗子
我们看看谁在撒谎！
- Liar! Liar!
- We'll see who's lying!
好吧，我去拿，但不要打架。好吧
OK, l'll get it, but no fighting. All right?
-我们要分开它。
-你不能分开一枚硬币。太蠢了。
- We'll split it.
- You can't split a coin. lt's stupid.
-是我的！我看到了
他说得对！你真蠢！
- lt's mine! l saw it!
- He's right! You're stupid!
那我们就买点东西分了。
Then we'll buy something and split that.
-你能不能别再指着我了？我见过。
-我也见过。
- Can you stop pointing? l've seen it.
- l've seen it, too.
好吧，如果不是那个小法国人
小法国人怎么样了？
Well, if it isn't the little Frenchman!
How is the little Frenchman?
好的
Fine.
你不介意我去吧？
You don't mind if l go instead, do you?
如果你介意，你会告诉我，不是吗？
lf you did mind, you'd tell me, no?
对
Yes.
很好。
Good.
计数
Count!
现在是谁的？
Whose is it now?
你看到了，但我很乐意。
You saw it, but l dove for it.
-罗伯托，还要多久？
-六！
- Roberto, how long?
- Six!
我把它扔回水里。
l throw it back into the water.
你下潜，如果你下潜不到六次，
You dive, and if you do less than six,
这是你的。
it's yours.
恩佐，我先看到了硬币。
我们要把它分开吗？
Enzo, l saw the coin first.
We'll split it?
我们不能分硬币，笨蛋！
We can't split a coin, stupid!
是不是。。。一枚硬币在那儿闪闪发光？
ls it... a coin shining there?
是的。这是一枚硬币。
lt is. lt's a coin.
我去给你拿，神父。
l'll get it for you, Father.
这是给穷人的。
lt will be for the poor.
神父！
Father!
该起床了，雅克。
Time to get up, Jacques.
倒霉。
Shit.
你不应该每天潜水，爸爸。
You shouldn't dive every day, Papa.
那你不应该每天都吃东西，雅克。
Then you shouldn't eat every day, Jacques.
别担心。当我累的时候，
Don't worry. When l am tired,
美人鱼帮了我。
the mermaids help me out.
嘿，你见过美人鱼吗？
Hey, have you ever seen a mermaid?
我见过他们。
l've seen them.
你不想知道在哪里吗？
Don't you want to know where?
你为什么不问问我？
Why don't you ask me?
-什么？
-我在哪里看到美人鱼。
- What?
- Where l saw mermaids.
你为什么不提任何问题？
总是提问题。
Why don't you ever ask any questions?
l always ask the questions.
我们到了，就像两块石头，现在我在自言自语。
Here we are, like two stones,
and now l'm talking to myself.
问我个问题，该死的！
Ask me something, goddamn it!
我妈妈为什么离开？
Why did my mother leave?
泵。
Pump.
你妈妈没有离开。
她回到了美国，仅此而已。
Your mother didn't leave.
She went back to America, that's all.
这是她的家。
lt's her home.
女人就是这样。
Women are like that.
不可预知的
Unpredictable.
就像大海。
Like the sea.
雅克！水！水！
Jacques! The water! Water!
救命啊！我不能呼吸了！
Help! l can't breathe!
号码
No!
爸爸？爸爸！
Daddy? Daddy!
等待呆在这儿，雅克！
Wait! Stay here, Jacques!
对这是怎么发生的？
Yes! How did it happen?
嗯，呃。。。公司要我从失事的船上搜出所有能找到的东西。
Well, uh... the company asked me to
extract everything l could from the wreck.
所以。。。潜水员们
正在试图接近引擎。。。
And so the... the divers
were trying to get at the engine...
船在水流中翻了过来！
and the boat just turned over
in the current!
听着，我。。。我搞砸了！
Look, l... l fucked up!
你看！
Look!
你能帮忙吗？
Can you help?
下面有多少人？
How many are down there?
只有一个。我们给他喂了很多空气
但是。。。他呼吸不正常。
There's just one. We're feeding him lots of air
but... he's not breathing properly.
你得把他弄出去，快点！
You've gotta get him outta there, fast!
一万块。
Ten thousand.
里尔？
Lire?
美元。
Dollars.
嘿，等等！
Hey, wait a minute!
你们不会在这样的时候把我抱起来吧？！
You guys aren't gonna try to
hold me up at a time like this?!
好吧，你告诉我。
OK, you tell me.
你认为一个人的生命值多少钱？
How much would you say
a man's life is worth?
在我的村子里我们有句俗语。
ln my village we have a saying.
又怎么样了？
How does it go again?
我不记得了。
l don't remember.
-这是什么意思？
-算了。
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Forget it.
恩佐！
Enzo!
福尔扎！
Forza!
既然我们时间不多，你就开那张支票？
Since we have a little time,
you write that cheque?
他还能干多久？
How much longer can he do that?
我哥哥。。。
My brother...
他是世界冠军。
is a world champion.
签名
Sign.
好极了！
Bravo!
好极了！好极了！
Bravo! Bravo!
谢谢好极了！
Thanks! Bravo!
嘿
Hey!
等待等一下！
Wait! Wait a minute!
等一下！等待嘿
Wait a minute! Wait! Hey!
嘿，谢谢你们。
Hey, thanks, you guys.
真正地我是认真的。
Really. l mean it.
不客气。
You're welcome.
一万美元，罗伯托！
Ten thousand dollars, Roberto!
你打算怎么处理这些钱？
What are you gonna do with the money?
把车漆一下。
Have the car painted.
但是朱塞佩要花25美元。
But Giuseppe will do that for 25 dollars.
那叫他也给它上蜡。
Then tell him to wax it, too.
-你到底想得到什么？
-给妈妈的念珠。。。
- What are you really gonna get?
- A rosary for Mamma...
…给安吉丽卡的裙子。。。
...a dress for Angelica...
…还有一套适合你的西装。
...and a suit that fits you.
但最重要的是。。。
But most important...
对
Yes?
给我找法国人。
Find me the Frenchman.
给我找雅克·马约尔。
Find me Jacques Mayol.
你是劳伦斯医生吗？
Are you Dr Laurence?
不，我是助理。
No. l'm the assistant.
欢迎来到秘鲁。
Welcome to Peru.
一杯热身的饮料？
A drink to warm up?
好的，谢谢。
Yes, please.
-茶还是威士忌？
-都是。
- Tea or whiskey?
- Both.
做我刚才看到一个穿着红色西装戴着护目镜的男人了吗？
Did... Did l just see a man
in a red suit and goggles?
正确的。
Right.
保险人来了。
The insurance person is here.
是时候了。
lt's about time.
乔安娜·贝克。
Johana Baker.
旅途愉快，嗯？
Nice trip, eh?
事故已经过去三个星期了。我们有点焦虑。
lt's three weeks since the accident.
We're getting a little anxious.
弗兰克，出去。他准备进去了。
Franck, get out there. He's ready to go in.
正确的。
Right.
第一次下潜，两分钟。
First dive, two minutes.
谁
Who...
那是谁？
Who is that?
马约尔。雅克·马约尔。
Mayol. Jacques Mayol.
那这些就是你的实验？
So those are your experiments?
把一个人扔到结冰的湖里？
Dumping a guy in a frozen lake?
卡车掉进一个很深的裂缝里。
The truck fell into a very deep crevasse.
我们没能救出设备。
We weren't able to rescue the equipment.
我得和司机谈谈。
l'll have to talk to the driver.
春天，当他融化的时候。
ln the spring, when he melts.
你真的要把他埋在冰下？
You really send him under the ice?
他不是奴隶或罪犯，不是吗？
He isn't a slave or a convict
or anything, is he?
亲爱的，科学是残酷的情妇。
My dear, science is a cruel mistress.
-他要怎么呼吸？
-他没有。
- How is he gonna breathe?
- He isn't.
听
Listen.
那是他的心声。
That's the sound of his heart.
你能听到它减速的速度吗？
Can you hear the speed
at which it's slowing down?
太不可思议了！
lt's incredible!
他现在在荧光镜里。
He's in the fluoroscope now.
听他的心跳！
Listen to his heartbeat!
真不敢相信！
l can't believe that!
所有的血液都集中在他的大脑里。
All the blood is concentrated in his brain.
它甚至不再喂他的四肢了。
lt doesn't even feed his limbs any more.
这是一种只在鲸鱼和海豚身上观察到的现象。
That's a phenomenon that's only
been observed in whales and dolphins.
直到现在。
Until now.
他为什么这么做？
Why is he doing this?
我不知道。
l don't know.
不应该有人给他拿毯子什么的吗？
Shouldn't someone take him
a blanket or something?
-我认识你。
-我们几分钟前刚见过面。
- l know you.
- We just met, a few minutes ago.
-在湖里？
-不。。。在小屋里。
- ln the lake?
- No... ln the hut.
那一定是长得很像你的人。
Then it must have been someone
who looked a lot like you.
这是礼物。
lt's a present.
你不打开吗？
Aren't you gonna open it?
你在这里很久了吗？
Are you here for a long time?
你住在哪里？
Where do you live?
在纽约。
ln New York.
很高兴见到你。
lt's been nice meeting you.
美好的我也是。
Nice... meeting you, too.
我只有五分钟。
l'll only be five minutes.
小丑。
Clown.
是只美洲驼。
lt's a llama.
大吉岭。
Darjeeling.
我想你们这些坏蛋。
l missed you rascals.
雅克，我的朋友。
Jacques, my friend.
你好吗？
How are you?
恩佐？
Enzo?
我让你游泳，20年后你还在水里。
l leave you swimming
and 20 years later you're still in the water.
你到底在干什么？培训？
What the hell are you doing? Training?
是 啊
Yeah.
很好。
Good.
看看这套衣服。
Check out the suit.
看起来不错，不是吗？
Looking good, no?
-你知道我是世界冠军吗？
-是的，我知道。
- You know l'm the world champion?
- Yeah, l know.
世界锦标赛
十天后在陶尔米纳开始。
The world championship
starts in ten days in Taormina.
请便。
Be my guest.
你的票。
Your ticket.
为什么？
Why?
因为我肯定你很想打败我。
Because l'm sure you're dying to beat me.
你是最棒的，恩佐。
You're the best, Enzo.
再见。
See you there.
L我听不见你说话！
l... l can't hear you!
我说雪地车的文件在杂物箱里。
l said the snowmobile papers
are in the glove compartment.
让海关给我寄一份。
Get the customs office to send me a copy.
在我们的文件完成之前，我们无法为您提供新设备。
We can't get you new equipment
until our file is complete.
好吧到本周末您将拥有它们。
All right. You'll have them
by the end of the week.
伟大的你让我成为一个非常快乐的保险人。非常感谢。
Great. You've made me a very happy
insurance person. Thank you.
-好吧。再见。
-劳伦斯博士？
- All right. Goodbye.
- Dr. Laurence?
对
Yes?
你不知道我怎么能和你的潜水员取得联系吗？
You don't happen to know how l can
get in touch with that diver of yours?
雅克·马约尔？
Jacques Mayol?
我最后一次听说他是在陶尔米纳参加世界跳水锦标赛的。
The last l heard he was in Taormina,
at the World Diving Championships.
在西西里。
ln Sicily.
马约尔。。。马约尔。。。没有预约。
Mayol... Mayol... No reservation.
-你确定吗？
-肯定，先生。
- Are you sure?
- Positive, sir.
这是圣多梅尼科酒店吗？
This is the Hotel San-Domenico?
是的，127年来一直如此。
Yes, it has been so for 127 years.
小心那辆车。这是新的油漆工作。好啊
Be careful of that car.
lt's a new paintjob. OK?
所以，你最终决定加入我们。
So, you finally decided to join us.
你做得对。
You did the right thing.
保罗，钥匙。
Paolo, the key.
你还记得我弟弟罗伯托吗？
You remember my little brother Roberto?
-嗨。
-嗨，罗伯托。
- Hi.
- Hi, Roberto.
-你有什么房间？
-我没有。
- What room have you got?
- l haven't got one.
你没有房间吗？保罗！
You don't have a room? Paolo!
我刚才听到什么了？我打电话给你为我的朋友雅克·马约尔预订一个房间。。。
What did l just hear? l call you to reserve
a room for my friend Jacques Mayol...
你把他当成陌生人！
and you treat him like a stranger!
-没事的，恩佐。我要去别的地方。
-他不仅是一个很特别的朋友。
- lt's OK, Enzo. l'll go somewhere else.
- Not only is he a very special friend.
但他是世界上最好的潜水员之一。你把他扔出去！
But he is one of the best divers
in the world. And you sling him out!
你疯了还是怎么了？
Are you crazy or what?
放下它，恩佐。我会找到东西的。
Drop it, Enzo. l'll find something.
拿我的。我要伯爵夫人的套房。
Take mine. l'll take the Countess's suite.
她告诉我她要去墓地。
She told me she was leaving
for the cemetery.
她在那里会更舒服！哈
She'll be more comfortable there! Ha!
很高兴你来了。
l'm glad you're here.
所以，这么多年了，你一定有很多问题要问我。我说得对吗？
So, after all these years, you must have
lots of questions to ask me. Am l right?
是的，当然，有很多问题。
Yeah, sure, lots of questions.
他们是什么？
Well, what are they?
我不知道怎么问这些问题。
l don't know how to ask the questions.
你结婚了吗？
Are you married?
我也是。因为我妈妈。
Me neither. Because of my mother.
她是个诅咒，我妈妈。龙卷风。
She's a curse, my mother. Tornado.
像骡子一样固执。
Stubborn as a mule.
我订婚一周了。
l was engaged for a week.
之后，妈妈很生气，意大利面从墙上弹了下来！
After, Mamma was so mad,
the pasta was bouncing off the walls!
所以，没有结婚。
So, not married.
真为你高兴。
Good for you.
你和我一样在球场上打球。每个港口都有一个女孩，嗯？
You play the field, like me.
A girl in every port, eh?
-毕竟，我们是男人
他妈的对！
- After all, we're men!
- Damn right!
当人们说你变成了一条鱼时，我就是这么告诉他们的。
That's what l tell them
when people say you've turned into a fish.
人们这么说？
People say that?
算了吧！我在开玩笑！
Forget it! l was joking!
我敢打赌她今晚在我床上。
l'll bet you my watch
that she's in my bed tonight.
-你们认识吗？
-认识！
- You know each other?
- Yes!
-恩佐·莫利纳里。非常荣幸。
-乔安娜·贝克。很高兴认识你。
- Enzo Molinari. This is a great pleasure.
- Johana Baker. Nice to meet you.
这是。。。一个巧合！难以置信！
This is... a coincidence! lt's unbelievable!
你想坐下吗？
Would you like to sit down?
-我没有打断任何事，是吗？
-不，一点也没有。
- l'm not interrupting anything, am l?
- No, not at all.
-你住在酒店吗？
-已经客满了。但他们推荐了一个。
- You staying at the hotel?
- lt's full. But they recommended a pensione.
-陶尔米纳的人都满了。
-这是自由跳水世界锦标赛。
- All of Taormina is full.
- lt's the Free Diving World Championship.
顺便说一下，我是世界冠军。
l am, by the way, world champion.
-你在西西里做什么？
-我在巴勒莫做保险索赔。。。
- What are you doing in Sicily?
- l was doing an insurance claim in Palermo...
决定休息几天，去岛上看看。
and decided to take a few days off,
see the island.
世界上没有比西西里岛更美的地方了。
There is no place in the world
more beautiful than Sicily.
意大利面德尔马
超级专注的保险代理人。
Spaghetti del mare
for the super-dedicated insurance agent.
就像我刚才说的，我是世界自由跳水冠军。
As l was saying earlier,
l am the world champion free diver.
有人说这是世界上最有男子气概的运动。
Some people say it's
the most virile sport in the world.
不得不承认看到那些人。。。
One has to admit that seeing those men...
在深蓝色的海里头朝下跳水，所有的肌肉都收缩了。。。
diving headfirst in that deep blue sea,
all muscles contracted...
-恩佐…
-什么？！
- Enzo...
- What?!
-妈妈？
-哪里？
- Mamma?
- Where?
等待
Wait.
如果她发现我在餐馆吃意大利面，她会杀了我的。
She'll kill me if she catches me
eating pasta in a restaurant.
快点吃完。
Eat up, quickly.
你认为我能自己拿这两个包吗？
You think l can carry these two bags
by myself?
妈妈。。。罗伯托和电梯。这还不够吗？
Mamma... Roberto and an elevator.
lsn't that enough?
-你今天吃了什么？
-只是一小杯咖啡。
- What have you had today?
- Just a small coffee.
我明天要潜水。啊，还记得小雅克吗？雅克·马约尔？
l am diving tomorrow. Ah,
remember little Jacques? Jacques Mayol?
还有他的朋友乔安娜。
And his friend, Johana.
她很漂亮，不是吗？
She is beautiful, no?
意大利面德尔马！
Spaghetti del mare!
我太饿了！
l'm so hungry!
欢迎
Welcome!
就是这样。
This is it.
所以，你这几天会很忙，是吗？
So, you're gonna be
really busy these days, eh?
我不知道。
l don't know.
为什么？
Why?
L因为我。。。
l... Because l...
我不知道。我只是想。。。
l don't know. l just thought...
你有比赛，面试。
You have the competition, interviews.
像这样的比赛需要
高度集中注意力。。。不是吗？
A competition like this requires
a great deal of concentration... Doesn't it?
你现在可以放下袋子了。
You can put down the bags now.
我们得为典礼做好准备。塔希提人是新的世界冠军。
We have to get ready for the ceremony.
The Tahitian is the new world champion.
我累了。我不喜欢。
l'm tired. l don't feel like it.
罗伯托，夹克。
Roberto, the jacket.
-这个？
-是的。
- This one?
- Yes.
非常好。
Very good.
那鞋子呢？
What about the shoes?
很别致。
Very chic.
-你没有别的东西了，是吗？
-没有。
- You don't have anything else, do you?
- No.
那就很别致了。走吧。
Then it's very chic. Let's go.
女士们先生们，请注意。
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please.
安德烈·博内，国际拳击锦标赛委员会主席。。。
Andre Bonnet, president of the International
Diving Championship Committee...
把这个奖杯献给新的世界冠军。
this trophy to the new world champion.
今天下午，我们的新冠军到达了非凡的深度。。。
This afternoon, our new champion
descended to the remarkable depth...
310英尺的高度。
of 310 feet.
一天的英雄。
A one-day hero.
总统先生，如果你愿意。。。
Mr President, if you please...
一项新的世界纪录。太好了。
A new world record. That's great.
它给了我明天要打败的东西。
lt gives me something to beat tomorrow.
你去过大溪地吗？
Have you ever been to Tahiti?
我带你去那儿。我们将生活在阳光下。
你将煮鲜鱼。。。
l'll take you there. We'll live in the sun.
You'll cook fresh fish...
我们会在椰子树下做爱。
and we'll make love
under the coconut trees.
嘿，等等。
你怎么做饭？
Hey, wait.
How about you do the cooking?
你忘了草裙舞。
And you forgot the hula.
请原谅我
Excuse me.
他看起来很奇怪，不是吗？
像个刚学会走路的婴儿。
He looks strange, doesn't he?
Like a baby who just learned to walk.
-你认识他很久了吗？
-永远。
- Have you known him long?
- For ever.
我们小时候住在希腊的同一个岛上。
We used to live on the same island in Greece,
when we were kids.
-他小时候是什么样子的？
-小。
- What was he like when he was little?
- Little.
很少。
Very little.
也就是说，和我相比。
That is, compared to me.
-我明白了，恩佐。你是个优秀的孩子。
-没错。
- l get it, Enzo. You were a superior child.
- Exactly.
怎么了，乔安娜？
What is it, Johana?
你对他那么着迷，
你不明白真相吗？
You are so crazy about him,
you don't see the truth?
不要把雅克当作一个人。他来自另一个世界。
Don't think of Jacques as a human being.
He is from another world.
你来自哪个世界，恩佐？
And just what world are you from, Enzo?
意大利！
ltalia!
现在，我的朋友们，
And now, my friends,
我们邀请你们在游泳池边喝一杯。
you are all invited for a drink
around the swim pool.
今天午餐时，你问我有什么问题。
Today, at lunch, you asked me
if l had any questions.
你终于想了解女人了！
You finally want to know about women!
-它们是最重要的吗？
-不是。
- Are they what's most important?
- No.
视情况而定。
lt depends.
有时他们是。
Sometime they are.
你到底想知道什么？
What exactly do you want to know?
一切。
Everything.
关于什么的一切？
Everything about what?
关于一切。
About everything.
所以，在妈妈，罗伯托和阿尔弗雷多之间，
So, between Mamma,
Roberto and Alfredo,
我们整天大喊大叫。
we yell and scream all day long.
除了当归。她只是哭。
Except with Angelica. She just cries.
最后，我们都接吻了。
And then, finally, we all end up kissing.
你能给我解释一下吗？
Can you explain that to me?
因为这就是爱的全部。
Because that's what love is all about.
真让人头疼，
lt's a pain in the ass,
但它让我们在一起。
but it keeps us together.
一个大的。。。
A large...
而且很漂亮。。。
and beautiful...
家庭
family.
我们必须退出这场比赛。
We've gotta quit this competition.
为什么？
Why?
余弦。。。如果我们不这么做，
Cos... if we don't,
我要打败你。
l'm gonna beat you.
你听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
-什么？
-他看着我的眼睛。。。
- What?
- He looks me in the eye...
就像一些该死的金鱼。。。
like some fucking goldfish...
然后说我要打败你。”
and says... "l'm gonna beat you."
你们来就是为了这个。
That's what you guys are here for.
哈听她的！
Ha! Listen to her!
他来这里就是为了这个！
That's what he's here for!
他是来输的
这就是他来这里的目的。
He's here to lose!
That's what he's here for.
首先，我是无敌的。
First of all, l am unbeatable.
第二
Second...
-你多大了？
-比你小两岁。
- How old are you?
- Two years younger than you.
就像我说的，
As l said,
其次，你太瘦了。
second of all, you're too skinny.
你的肺很小。我还是不明白
你怎么能潜水而不生病。
You've got tiny lungs. l still don't understand
how you can dive without getting sick.
肺部的大小
与此无关。
The size of the lungs
has nothing to do with it.
你能屏住呼吸多久？
How long can you hold your breath?
比你长。
Longer than you.
嘿别紧张！上帝啊
Hey! Take it easy! Jesus!
你疯了吗？
Are you mad?
来吧，我来帮你。
Come on, let me help you with this.
-谁赢了？
-什么？混蛋奖？
- Who won?
- What? The Asshole Award?
让我告诉你，那是一条领带。
Let me tell you, it was a tie.
表现得像一对两岁的孩子。
Acting like a pair of two-year-olds.
你可能死在那个池子里了。
You could've died in that pool.
别动。你把船摇起来了。
Stop moving. You're rocking the boat.
很幸运，我是来救你的。
Luckily, l was there to save you.
我的钱包。
My wallet.
-在这里。
-不，不。我想给你看。
- lt's here.
- No, no. l wanna show you.
把它给我。
Give it to me.
坐下来
Sit down.
那是我的家人。
That's my family.
什么样的人。。。
What kind of man...
有这样的家庭吗？
has such a family?
没事的。
lt's OK.
lt's all right.
所有的医生都在找你，恩佐。
All the medics are looking for you, Enzo.
我在冥想！你看不见吗？
l am meditating! Can't you see?
雅克在下床前做了两个小时的瑜伽！
Jacques does two hours of yoga
before going down!
我可以小睡五分钟！
l can have a five-minute nap!
莫里纳里先生，对不起，
Mr Molinari, l am sorry,
但你不能在这种精疲力竭的状态下潜水。
but you cannot dive
in this state of exhaustion.
你对大海了解多少？
什么都不知道！
What do you know about the sea?
Nothing!
所以你就把管子和罐头拿走。
So you just take your tubes
and your tin cans away.
大海是我的。
The sea is mine.
我知道她什么时候准备好了，什么时候没有。
l know when she is ready for me
and when she isn't.
今天她准备好了。
And today she is ready.
你自担风险潜水。
You dive at your own risk.
一分钟！
One minute!
你的裤子对我来说太大了。
Your trousers are too big for me.
他们在哪里？
Where are they?
-所有人都去哪了？
-他们走了。
- Where is everybody?
- They're gone.
出事了。
Something's wrong.
你不能那样做。
You can't do that.
怎么了
What's the matter?
我不明白。
l don't understand.
我已经试了两天了。他们不吃东西。
l've tried for two days. They won't eat.
他们不会表演的。
They won't perform.
自从我们有了新的。
Since we got a new one.
今天结束了。
lt's finished for today.
她是新来的。
She's a new one.
你怎么知道是女的？
How can you tell it's a female?
这是她移动的方式。
lt's the way she moves.
别难过。我只收回了我的东西。
Don't be sad.
l only took back what was mine.
在这里一份礼物。
Here. A present.
今晚我们有一个小小的聚会。八点钟在我的套房。
Tonight we're having a little party
among ourselves. Eight o'clock in my suite.
罗伯托先生，告诉你哥哥要讲道理。
Mr Roberto, tell your brother
to be reasonable.
大家都在楼上等他。
Everybody's waiting for him upstairs.
他不能！他不舒服！
He can't! He's indisposed!
我们去叫医生好吗？
Shall we call a doctor?
不，不！妈妈，她在尝试什么！
No, no! La Mamma,
she is trying something!
马约尔先生，帮帮我们。
Mr Mayol, help us.
他拒绝接受勋章，大家都在等他。
He refuses to receive his medal,
and everybody's waiting for him.
-我会尽力的。
-你真是太好了。
- l'll do my best.
- That's very kind of you.
我是雅克！
lt's Jacques!
我的朋友！进来吧！
My friend! Come on in!
莫里纳里先生，请允许我给你留下深刻印象。。。
Mr Molinari,
allow me to impress upon you...
出席颁奖典礼的重要性。。。
the importance of your attending
the award ceremony...
对媒体来说。
for the press.
我想我哥哥告诉过你我不舒服。
应该这样做，不是吗？
l think my brother told you l was indisposed.
That should do it, no?
我可以不舒服，对吧？
l am allowed to be indisposed, right?
所以你去告诉媒体，
So you just go tell the press
that the big Enzo Molinari,
被他那令人振奋的324英尺的降落伞压得喘不过气来，
overwhelmed by his inspiring descent
of 324 feet,
将无法收到他的小饰物。。。
will not be able to receive his trinket...
因为他是。。。
because he is...
-嗯？
-。。他是。。。
- Hm?
-.. he is...
不舒服
Indisposed!
雅克，我的朋友！
Jacques, my friend!
-你为什么不拿起你的勋章？
-因为意大利面应该吃得很好！
- Why don't you pick up your medal?
- Because pasta should be eaten al dente!
告诉我你怎么找到的。
Let me know how you find it.
我在纽约的办公室。那里真的很忙。
My office in New York.
lt's really busy back there.
我有很多工作要做。
l have so much work to do.
-你想要一些吗？
-哦，不。
- Do you want some?
- Oh, no.
怎么了
What's the matter?
我得请你帮个忙。
l have to ask you a favour.
嘿，我们不是在偷海豚吧？
Hey, we're not stealing a dolphin, eh?
不，我告诉过你，我们只是帮一个人。
No. l told you, we're just helping one out.
想帮个忙吗？
Trying to help one out?
很好。
Good.
夜晚的陶尔米娜
幸运的海豚，嗯？
Taormina by night!
Lucky dolphin, eh?
是 啊楼梯！
Yeah! Stairs!
你现在可以停下来了。
她需要的水都有了。
You can stop that now.
She has all the water she needs.
好吧，我们做到了
咱们回去参加聚会吧。
All right, we did it!
Let's go back to the party.
五分钟，就这样！好啊
Five minutes, that's all! OK?
晚安。
Night.
-晚安，雅克。晚安。
- Good night, Jacques.
- Good night.
你不需要担架把她带走。
You don't need a stretcher
to take her with you.
-你知道吗？
-什么？
- You know that?
- What?
海豚不是唯一一个有时感觉不太好的人。
Dolphins aren't the only ones
who don't feel very good sometimes.
雅克
明天我能看你潜水吗？
Jacques!
Can l watch you dive tomorrow?
关于女人，你确实有一些东西要学。
You really do have
a few things to learn about women.
那些家伙是干什么的？
What do those guys do?
他们是医护人员。
They are paramedics.
他们在200英尺处等待。
They wait at 200 feet.
他呢？
And him?
那就是潜到300英尺以下的潜水员。
That is the diver who goes below 300 feet.
他用氦氧混合物潜水。压缩空气太危险了。
He dives with a helium-oxygen mixture.
Compressed air is too dangerous.
三分钟！
Three minutes!
他跌到了360英尺！
He went down to 360 feet!
恭喜你，雅克。太好了。我为你高兴。
Congratulations, Jacques.
lt's wonderful. l'm happy for you.
在这里
Here.
-是什么？
-小礼物。没什么。
- What is it?
- Little presents. Nothing much.
我就知道。我就知道。
l knew it. l just knew it.
你还在收吗？
Do you still collect them?
你没有那个，是吗？
You don't have that one, do you?
很漂亮。非常感谢。
lt's beautiful. Thank you.
没什么。
lt's nothing.
我就知道。我告诉罗伯托了。
l knew it. l told Roberto.
他很好，那个小法国人。
很好。
He's very good, that little Frenchman.
Very good.
这是首诗吗？
ls this a poem?
不，这是意大利面的配方。
No, it's a recipe
for spaghetti frutti del mare.
我把你带到这里是对的。你是世界冠军，我的朋友。
l was right in getting you out here.
You're a world champion, my friend.
是卷尺。
lt's a measuring tape.
你看到了吗？这是你的唱片。
You see? This is your record.
比我的高三英尺。
Three feet more than mine.
从这里看，它看起来不怎么样，是吗？
Looking at it from here,
it doesn't look like much, does it?
留着你的小卷尺，我的朋友。
Keep your little measuring tape, my friend.
下次我打败你时，这将是一个很好的纪念品。
lt will be a nice souvenir
when l beat you next.
你今晚过得愉快吗？
Did you have a nice night?
是 啊
Yeah.
我和海豚在一起。
l was with the dolphin.
整晚？
All night?
是 啊
Yeah.
-和海豚在一起？
-是的。
- With the dolphin?
- Yeah.
我得回纽约了。
l gotta get back to New York.
因为我有我的工作，我有我的工作，我的。。。生活
Because l have my job,
l have my work and my... life.
你能带我去火车站吗？
Will you take me to the train station?
如果你来过纽约，给我打个电话，好吗？
lf you're ever in New York,
give me a call, OK?
-我能进来吗？
-没问题。我喜欢在睡梦中说话。
- Can l come in?
- No problem. l enjoy talking in my sleep.
11点叫醒我。
Wake me up at 11.
你为什么老是说话？没人关心你在说什么。
Why are you always talkin'? Nobody's
interested in what you're talkin' about.
所以别说了！其他人
有话要说！明白吗？
So just stop talkin'! Other people
have things to say! Understand?
别说了！胡说八道！
Stop talkin'! lt's bullshit!
-她走了？
-是的，她走了！
- She's gone?
- Yes, she's gone!
嘿，我会照顾你的。
Hey, l'm gonna take care of you.
我有份工作，在石油钻台上。
l've got a job, on an oil rig.
举手之劳
No sweat.
我带你一起去。好啊
l'm taking you along. OK?
快点，收拾好你的行李。
你跟我来。
Come on, get your bags packed.
You're coming with me.
你这个蠢货。
You stupid bastard.
我们会成为一个伟大的团队，我们两个。
We'll make a great team, the two of us.
你会看到的。
You'll see.
好啊
OK?
100英尺。
100 feet.
你还在想她。
You're still thinking about her.
别再想她了。
Don't think about her any more.
世界上有那么多女人。
There are so many women in the world.
到处都是女人。对吗？
Plenty of women everywhere. Right?
吸烟是绝对禁止的。
Smoking is absolutely forbidden.
还没亮呢。
lt isn't lit yet.
你甚至不应该在船上放香烟。
You shouldn't even
carry cigarettes on board.
听着，我们也不能小便。
Listen, we're not supposed to piss, either.
但这并不能阻止你把它带上飞机。
But that doesn't stop you
from carrying it on board.
规则就是规则。
The rules are the rules.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name again?
诺伊特。
Noireuter.
你说你是哪里人？
And where did you say you were from?
布鲁塞尔。
Brussels.
我17岁。
l was 17.
我太爱她了，我想为她而死。
l loved her so much, l tried to die for her.
两年后，
Two years later,
我都记不起她的名字了。
l couldn't even remember her name.
我告诉你，
时间会抹去一切。
Let me tell you,
time erases everything.
我不想抹掉任何东西。
l don't want to erase anything.
450英尺。下降结束。
450 feet. End of descent.
我们在这里停留50分钟。
We'll be left here for 50 minutes.
你的声音怎么了？
What's with the voice?
没什么。
可能氦太高了。
lt's nothing.
Maybe the helium is up too high.
-声音恢复了吗？
-对于其他人，是的。
- Does the voice come back?
- For others, yes.
为你。。。谁知道呢？
For you... Who knows?
试着跟我说话。
Try speaking to me.
我觉得这不好笑。
我们在认真交谈！
l don't find this funny.
We were having a serious conversation!
氦气没问题。
lt's OK for the helium.
给，把你的手指给我。
Here, give me your finger.
那是酒精吗？
这是禁止的！
ls that alcohol?
That's really forbidden!
嘿，你还有别的抱怨吗？
Hey, do you have any other complaints?
列一张单子，我们把它贴在舷窗上。好啊
Make a list and we'll stick it
on the porthole. OK?
-吮吸你的手指。
-别开玩笑了。这是。。。
- Suck your finger.
- Stop kidding around. lt's...
在这种压力下很危险-酒精。
lt's dangerous at this pressure - alcohol.
恩佐，这里很深。
Enzo, it's very deep down here.
来吧，吮吸你的手指。
Come on, suck your finger.
啊，你会看到
到处都是医务人员。
Ah, you'll be seeing
mermaids everywhere.
一千名指挥官，我们从“嗜酒者匿名”那里得到了比利时人！
A thousand commanders and we get
the Belgian from Alcoholics Anonymous!
明白了吗？
Are we clear?
你能听见我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
我是乔安娜。
lt's Johana.
你好吗？
How are you?
我被解雇了。
l got fired.
我得到了恩佐的这份工作。
l got this job with Enzo.
我们也被解雇了。
We got fired, too.
真正地
Really?
很奇怪。
lt's strange.
再跟我说几句。
Talk to me some more.
这很难。我不知道还能说什么。
你离我太远了。
lt's hard. l don't know what else to say.
You're so far away.
给我讲个故事。
Tell me a story.
一个故事？
A story?
你知道这是怎么回事吗。。。
Do you know how it is...
你知道为了遇见美人鱼你应该做什么吗？
Do you know what you're supposed to do
to meet a mermaid?
你下到海底。。。
You go down to the bottom of the sea...
水不再是蓝色了。。。
where the water isn't even blue any more...
天空只是一个记忆。。。
and the sky is only a memory...
你漂浮在那里，在寂静中，
and you float there, in the silence,
你呆在那里。。。
and you stay there...
你决定。。。你会为他们而死。
and you decide... that you'll die for them.
只有到那时他们才会出来。
Only then do they start comin' out.
他们来迎接你，并且审判你对他们的爱。
They come, and they greet you,
and they judge the love you have for them.
如果是真心的话，
lf it's sincere,
如果是纯的，
if it's pure,
他们会和你在一起。。。
they'll be with you...
把你永远带走。
and take you away for ever.
我喜欢这个故事。
l like that story.
这是怎么一回事？
What is it?
我想我爱你。
l think l love you.
你住在这里？
You live here?
是 啊有时候。
Yeah. Sometimes.
-那是谁？
-那是我叔叔路易斯。
- Who's that?
- That's my Uncle Louis.
我不能把他从浴缸里弄出来。
l can't get him out of the bathtub.
莎辛那
Assassin!
路易斯叔叔
这是我的朋友乔安娜！
Uncle Louis!
This is my friend Johana!
乔安娜来看我了！
Johana is visiting me!
他有点聋。他75岁了。
He's a bit deaf. He's 75.
很高兴见到你，路易斯叔叔！
lt's very nice to meet you, Uncle Louis!
那么，你从哪里来，亨利埃塔？
So, where are you from, Henrietta?
乔安娜！纽约！
Johana! New York!
纽约？那是什么名字？
New York? What kind of name is that?
-不，我是从纽约来的。
-哦，是的！
- No, l'm from New York.
- Oh, yeah!
最好的腿来自纽约！
The best legs are from New York!
路易斯叔叔。。。
Uncle Louis...
乔安娜是我的朋友。
Johana is my friend.
她来了。。。跟我在一起。。。
She's come to... stay with me...
一段时间。
for a while.
很好。那样我会见到更多的你。
Good. That way l'll see more of you.
你要住在哪里？
Where are you gonna stay?
-这里。
-这里？在我公寓里？
- Here.
- Here? ln my apartment?
这是我的公寓。
lt's my apartment.
说谎者！作弊！折磨者！
Liar! Cheat! Torturer!
路易斯叔叔，回你的浴缸去。
Uncle Louis, go back to your bathtub.
我要把电话锁上。
l'm going to put a lock on the telephone.
再喝点酒，路易斯叔叔。
Have some more wine, Uncle Louis.
谢谢你，亨利埃塔。
Thank you, Henrietta.
我要改名了。
l'll change my name.
这是，呃。。。
This is, er...
我的房间。
my room.
恩佐打电话来。他下周过来参加另一场比赛。
Enzo phoned. He's coming over next week
for another competition.
你也要参加比赛吗？
Are you gonna compete, too?
是 啊
Yeah.
你确定你在这里没事吗？
Are you sure you'll be all right here?
他不喜欢迟到。
lt's not like him to be late.
当然，
有时他根本不出现。
Of course,
sometimes he doesn't show up at all.
两美元？！
Two dollars?!
你甚至不需要抓鱼！
You didn't even need to catch the fish!
它死于癌症！
lt died of cancer!
-你从哪儿弄来的？
-那个？这不是“那”。
- Where did you get that?
- That? This is not a "that".
这位是西班牙著名女演员波妮塔·玛丽波莎，
This is Bonita Mariposa,
the famous Spanish actress,
谁会对清漆非常小心。。。
who is going to be very careful
with the varnish...
…和他一起
几天。
...and who is spending
a few days with us.
-妈妈在哪？
-你还有8个小时她才能到。
- Where is Mamma?
- You have 8 hours before she gets here.
他真的快聋了。
He's really going totally deaf.
我没有你瞎那么聋！
l'm not as deaf as you are blind!
你管好你的眼睛，我管好我的耳朵！
You take care of your eyes,
and l'll take care of my ears!
对不起，路易斯叔叔。
l'm sorry, Uncle Louis.
快点，喝吧，孩子！
Come on, drink up, my boy!
嘿，告诉我，你在哪个世纪？
Hey, tell me, what century are you in?
第二
Second.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on here?
我们在听音乐。
和恩佐。
We're listening to some music.
With Enzo.
-我是劳伦斯医生。
-啊！
- This is Dr Laurence.
- Ah!
所以，你一定是著名的
Enzo Molinari。
So, you must be the famous
Enzo Molinari.
在肉体上！我有这个荣幸。
ln the flesh! l have that honour.
上帝我有皱纹了。
God... l'm getting wrinkles.
嗯，嗯。我长痘痘了。
Mm-hm. And l'm getting pimples.
那么，你会永远住在这里吗？
So, are you gonna live here permanently?
我不知道。
事情发生得太快了。
l don't know.
Things have happened so fast.
我们还没谈过呢。
We haven't even talked about it.
你非常相爱。我看得出来。
You're very much in love. l can tell.
你有那种表情。
You have that look.
想要孩子的女人的样子。
The look of a woman who wants a baby.
我都没想过要孩子。
l haven't even thought of having a baby.
天啊，我们只是。。。开始互相了解。那真的。。。
God, we're just... starting
to get to know each other. lt'd be really...
真的吗？
Do l really?
嗯，也许他还没准备好，但是。。。
Well, maybe he's not quite ready, but...
他是个好人，很敏感。
he's a nice guy, sensitive.
我不能一个人生孩子。
Well, l can't have a baby by myself.
为什么不呢？我有个孩子。
Why not? l have a baby.
我爱他的父亲。
l loved his father.
我们不再在一起了但是。。。
We're not together any more but...
我有他的孩子。
l have his baby.
最后，你还是一个人做。
At the end, you do it alone anyway.
用于分类的Enzo Molinari。
Enzo Molinari for classification.
他最后一次是什么时候？
What was his last time?
我不知道，但时间真的很长。
l don't know, but it was really long.
嘿，还不错。
Hey, that's not bad.
很好，恩佐。非常好。
Very good, Enzo. Very good.
那又怎么样？任何人都可能有糟糕的一天。
So what? Anybody can have a bad day.
好吧，当大海不需要你的时候，我已经有很多次了。
Well, l've had many,
when the sea doesn't want you.
从来都不是大海。是妈妈，罗伯托，那个愚蠢的女演员！
lt's never the sea.
lt's Mamma, Roberto, that stupid actress!
别打断我的球。
Don't break my balls.
你今天过得愉快吗？
Did you have a nice day?
恩佐今天过得不好。
Enzo had a bad day.
你潜水了吗？
Did you dive?
不，感觉不对。
No, it didn't feel right.
是个可爱的孩子，嗯？
我喜欢那个孩子。
lt's a cute baby, eh?
l love that baby.
让他们试试。
Let them try.
他没事吧？
ls he OK?
他们在做什么？
What are they doing?
我不知道。
l don't know.
太棒了！
Great time!
怎么样？
How was it?
很危险。
lt was dangerous.
380英尺，
380 feet,
水下4分50秒。
four minutes and 50 seconds underwater.
伟大的
Great.
非常感谢。非常感谢你。
Thank you. Thank you very much.
我的儿子，太棒了！
My son, bravo!
现在。。。
Now...
我相信你听到一些人说这对我们来说太危险了，不能继续下去。
l am sure you heard some people suggest
it is too dangerous for us to continue.
危险，因为我们不知道如何测量。。。
Dangerous because
we don't know how to measure...
这种潜水的生理后果。
the physiological consequences
of this type of dive.
也因为潜水者不习惯潜到300英尺以下。
And also because the scuba divers
are not used to going down below 300 feet.
-但是…
-他在说什么？
- But...
- What's he saying?
…我们问了自由潜水员，
...we asked the free divers,
他们都坚持。。。
and they all insist...
竞争还在继续。
that the competition continue.
祝你们好运。祝你好运
Good luck to you all. Good luck.
一分钟！
One minute!
你不能呆在这里！
You can't stay here!
你看见他了吗？
Do you see him?
嘿你看见他了吗？
Hey! Do you see him?
雅克！
Jacques!
400英尺。
400 feet.
400英尺！
400 feet!
你没事吧？
You all right?
我马上就到！
l'll be right there!
你好进来吧。
Hi! Come on in.
-不，我想说再见。
-你要走了？
- No. l wanted to say goodbye.
- You're leaving?
是的。
你能把这个给恩佐吗？
Yes.
Could you please give this to Enzo?
没用的。
lt's no use.
告诉他我说再见了，然后给他一个吻。好啊
Just tell him l said goodbye,
and give him a kiss for me. OK?
-答应？
-答应。
- Promise?
- Promise.
也许你不该这么轻易放弃。
Maybe you shouldn't give up so easily.
这是给你的礼物。
Here's a present for you.
是你的孩子。
lt's your baby.
相信我，它会改变你的生活，
Believe me, it will change your life,
只是为了更好。
only for the better.
你照顾好自己，乔安娜。
You take care of yourself, Johana.
你也是。
You, too.
欢迎来到希腊，雅克
你好吗？
Welcome to Greece, Jacques!
How are you?
欢迎，乔安娜。祝您旅途愉快？
Welcome, Johana. Have a good trip?
好的，让我告诉你所有的信息。
跟我来。
OK, let me give you all the information.
Come with me.
这让我恶心。
This is making me sick.
为什么？
Why?
你能给我一杯水吗？
Would you give me a glass of water?
对竞争感到紧张吗？
Nervous about the competition?
你潜水的时候是什么感觉？
What's it feel like when you dive?
这是一种滑倒而不摔倒的感觉。
lt's a feeling of slipping without falling.
最难的是当你触底的时候。
The hardest thing is when
you hit the bottom.
为什么？
Why?
因为你必须找到一个好的理由回来。
Because you have to find
a good reason to come back up.
我很难找到一个。
And l have a hard time finding one.
我们也有同样的问题。
Well, we have the same problem.
为什么？
Why?
因为我很难找到留下来的理由。
Because l have a hard time
finding a good reason to stay.
我找到一个。
l found one.
他在吗？
ls he here?
是 啊
Yeah.
很好。
Good.
当你在海里那样看我时，我很害怕。
lt scares me when you look
at the sea like that.
我小时候常在这里潜水。
l used to dive here when l was a boy.
我有事要跟你谈谈。
l have something
l want to talk to you about.
不在这里。
Not here.
我们能在这里谈谈吗？
Can we talk here?
让我们谈谈我的世界。
Let's talk about my world.
我的世界就是你。
My world is you.
我爱你。
l love you.
我想和你住在一起。
l wanna live with you.
我想和你生个孩子。
l wanna have a baby with you.
我想和你住一栋房子。
l wanna have a house with you.
你有车。一只狗和你在一起。
A car with you. A dog with you.
你知道的？
You know?
雅克，我想我可能怀孕了！
Jacques, l think l might be pregnant!
你听见了吗？
Did you hear me?
明天将是重要的一天。
Tomorrow is going to be a big day.
当我分析了约尔最后一次潜水的数据时，它变得很明显。
When l analysed the data from
Mayol's last dive, it became apparent.
在这些人潜水的深处，这在生理上是不可能的。。。
At the depths these men are diving,
it is a physiological impossibility...
它们能保留足够的氧气到达表面。
that they could retain enough oxygen
to make it to the surface.
压力太大，阻止氧气在体内循环。
The pressure is so strong, it stops the oxygen
from circulating through the body.
试图打破马约尔的记录。。。
To attempt to break Mayol's record now...
就是简单的自杀。
is simple suicide.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
是的，我明白。
Yes, l understand.
今天只是训练。
Today is just training.
-莫里纳里是17次世界冠军。
-三分钟！
- Molinari is a 17-time world champion.
- Three minutes!
你想告诉他他不会跳水吗？
Do you want to tell him he can't dive?
取消比赛。
Cancel the competition.
两分钟！
Two minutes!
把梅约带进来。
Get Mayol in here.
一分钟！
One minute!
他们想取消比赛。
They wanna cancel the competition.
一段时间。
For a while.
为什么？
Why?
他们说这不安全。
lt's not safe, they say.
医生说。。。
The doctors say...
我们不能再深入下去了。
we can't go deeper and survive.
你这么说是因为你有头衔。
You say that because you have the title.
我绝不会欺骗你。
l would never cheat you.
你真好。
That's very nice of you.
哦，天哪
l让你告诉他不要去！
Oh, Jesus!
l told you to tell him not to go!
不是我的错！我告诉他了！
lt's not my fault! l told him!
-不，不，不
然后他们就死了！
- No, no, no!
- And then they die!
这是我第一次组织比赛！
lt's the first time
l've organised a competition!
精彩的！
Wonderful!
逃掉
Get away!
你能走开吗？！
Will you get away?!
他妈的！
Goddamn it!
逃掉
Get away!
-给他点时间！别管他
出去！
- Give him some time! Leave him alone!
- Out!
走开！
Clear off!
你是对的。
You were right.
关于什么？
About what?
下面好多了。
lt's much better down there.
这是个更好的地方。
lt's a better place.
把我推回水中。
Push me back in the water.
不，我不能。
No, l can't.
带我回去。
Take me back down.
请
Please.
嘿，看！
Hey, look!
-举起手臂。。。越过顶端…
-来吧，雅克。
- Up with the arms... Over the top...
- Come on, Jacques.
让我们心跳一下。
Let's get a heartbeat.
快，呼吸！
Come on, breathe!
快点，雅克。快点，雅克！
Come on, Jacques. Come on, Jacques!
回来，雅克！
Come back, Jacques!
雅克！跟我们在一起！
Jacques! Stay with us!
很好。很好。
Good. Good.
好孩子。
Good boy.
非常好。
Very good.
在这里
Here.
睡一觉。
Get some sleep.
我们稍后再谈。
We'll talk later.
你现在睡觉。
You sleep now.
我爱你。
l love you.
劳伦斯医生…
这是给你的。
Doctor Laurence...
This just arrived for you.
我不在船上。
l wasn't on the boat.
20年来唯一一次，
The only time in 20 years,
我不在船上。
and l wasn't on the boat.
我得走了，告诉妈妈。
l must go now, tell Mamma.
我知道现在不是时候，但是。。。
l know this isn't a good time for this, but...
我这里有你的测试结果。
l have the results of your test here.
是的，你怀孕了。
Yes, you're pregnant.
你高兴吗？
Are you happy?
-是的。
-很好。
- Yes.
- Good.
我很高兴。
l'm happy.
我很害怕，
l'm scared,
但我很高兴。
but l'm happy.
所以
So...
别再胡闹了。
no more ouzo.
别再抽烟了。
No more cigarettes.
-你保重。
-谢谢。
- You take care.
- Thank you.
这是怎么一回事？跟我说话！
What is it? Talk to me!
好啊等一下。
OK. Wait a minute.
让我们和劳伦斯谈谈。
Let's talk to Laurence.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
拜托，拜托别这样。
Please, please don't do this.
听着，别这样！
Look, don't do this!
你为什么这么做？
Why are you doing this?
雅克。。。跟我说！
Jacques... Just talk to me!
我得去看看。
l've got to go and see.
看到什么了？
See what?
没什么可看的，雅克！
There's nothing to see, Jacques!
下面很黑！太冷了！
lt's dark down there! lt's cold!
你会一个人的！
You'll be alone!
我在这里！我是真的！我存在！
And l'm here! l'm real! l exist!
我怀孕了。
l'm pregnant.
你没听见吗？
Didn't you hear me?